&gt；&gt；Kyle Simpson：那么我们可以用这些作用域的知识做什么呢？
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: So what can we do with this knowledge of scopes?
具体地说，我们一直专注于按功能组织的作用域。
And, specifically, we've been focusing on scopes that are organized by functions.
我们能用它做什么？
What can we do with that?
它能帮助我们解决什么样的能力或问题？
What sorts of abilities or problems does it help us solve?
这不仅仅是理论上的。
It's not just theoretical.
我们这样做是因为我们试图建立一种模式，帮助我们
We are doing this because we're trying to build towards a pattern that helps us
更好地组织我们的代码。
organize our code better.
因此，为了朝着这个模式构建，让我们开始用我们的函数来做一些事情。
So to build towards that pattern, let's start doing things with our functions.
让我们来谈谈这个例子，显然非常简单和愚蠢。
Let's talk about this example, obviously very simple and silly.
但是我们有一个变量，然后在程序的后面我们使用这个变量。
But we have a variable, and then later in the program we are using the variable.
我们希望它仍然有同样的价值。
And we're hoping that it still has the same value.
现在一切看起来都很好。
Right now, everything looks good.
但六个月后，一个初级开发人员，不知道他们在做什么，
But six months from now, a junior developer, not knowing what they're doing,
不是因为他们笨，而只是因为他们没有看到，不知道，
not because they're dumb but just simply because they didn't see it, not knowing,
并在两者之间插入此代码。
comes along and inserts this code in between.
&gt；&gt；Kyle Simpson：您可以立即发现问题，存在名称冲突。
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: You can immediately spot the problem, there's a name collision.
他们选择命名他们的变量
They chose to name their variable
与该作用域中已经存在的变量相同。
the same as the variable that already existed in that scope.
当他们在第6行重写时，
And when they overwrote it on line 6,
它以一种不明显的方式破坏了第10行。
it ended up breaking line 10 in a non-obvious way.
&gt；&gt；Kyle Simpson：现在，你可能在想，好吧，
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: Now, you might be thinking to yourself, well,
这就是为什么我应该用常量。
that's why I should have used a const.
但那并不能真正解决这个问题。
Except that wouldn't really have fixed this.
它会向初级开发人员抛出一个错误，
It would've thrown an error to a junior developer,
这样的话，他可能会把你的const改成var。
who then probably would have just changed your const to a var anyway.
这并不能真正解决这个问题。
That doesn't really fix this problem.
真正的问题，真正的根本问题，不是那个
The real problem, the real root problem, is not that
变量可以被重新分配，但是我们有一个命名冲突的问题。
the variable could be reassigned, but that we have a naming collision problem.
&gt；&gt；Kyle Simpson：我们遇到了一个问题，两个不同的实体想要使用相同的
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: We have a problem where two different entities wanna use the same
用于某种目的语义名称。
semantic name for some purpose.
&gt；&gt；扬声器1：在同一范围内。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 1: In the same scope.
&gt；&gt；Kyle Simpson：在相同的范围内。
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: In the same scope.
那么，我们如何解决这个问题，我们不能有两个不同的
So how do we resolve this problem where we can't have two different
同一作用域中相同名称的用法没有冲突，
usages of the same name in the same scope without them conflicting,
不会发生碰撞，但我们怎么解决这个问题呢？
without them colliding, but how do we fix that?
当然，我们可以把它们放在不同的桶里。
Well, naturally, we could put them in different buckets.
到目前为止，我们看到的最好的方法是围绕它包装一个函数。
And the best way that we've seen thus far Is to wrap a function around it.
所以如果我在这里创建另一个Teacher函数
So if I make anotherTeacher function here and
我将第4行声明为变量，现在它是一个不同颜色的大理石，对吗？
I declare line 4 that variable, now it's a different colored marble, right?
这是蓝色大理石，不是红色大理石。
It's a blue marble, not a red marble.
这样该变量就不会与第10行中的变量发生冲突，
So that variable doesn't end up conflicting with the one in line 10,
一切都还有效。
everything still works.
问题是，现在我有了一个在该作用域中具有名称的函数。
The problem is that now I have a function that has a name in that scope.
它的名称是另一个Teacher。
It has the name anotherTeacher.
所以我根本没有解决命名冲突问题，是吗？
So I didn't really fix the naming collision problem at all, did I?
我只是把它换成了一个不同的变量名。
I just shifted it to a different variable name.
&gt；&gt；Kyle Simpson：没错，我们现在有了一个新的作用域，我们可以包含
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: It is true that we now have a new scope, and we can contain
该作用域的任何赋值，但我们仍然存在命名冲突问题。
any assignments of that scope, but we still have a naming collision problem.
&gt；&gt；Kyle Simpson：软件开发中有一个原则，叫做
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: There's a principle within software development, it's called
最小暴露原则或最小特权原则，
the principle of least exposure or the principle of least privilege,
取决于你拥有的维基百科页面或CS教科书。
depending on which Wikipedia page or which CS textbook you had.
无论是哪种方式，不管它叫什么，最小暴露的原则
Either way, whatever it's called, the principle of least exposure or
特权说的。
privilege says this.
您应该默认将所有内容都保持私密，并且
You should default to keeping everything private, and
只暴露最低限度的必要。
only exposing the minimal necessary.
&gt；&gt；Kyle Simpson：这是软件工程的核心原则之一，
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: That's one of the core principles of software engineering,
因为它本质上建立了一种防御姿态。
because it essentially sets up a defensive posture.
这是一种防御性的方法，它说，我不想让我的东西可用
It's a defensive approach that says, I don't wanna make my stuff available
因为我不想遇到这种问题。
because I don't want these sorts of problems.
事实上，我们通过这个解决了三个主要问题
As a matter of fact, there are three main problems that we solve by this
最小暴露或最不流行原则的防御方法。
defensive approach of the least exposure or least prevalent principle.
第一，我们有命名冲突的问题。
Number one, we have naming collision problems.
如果您在一个范围内隐藏了一些东西，或者在名称空间中隐藏了一些东西或做了什么
And if you hide something within a scope, or hide something on a namespace or do
其他类型的隐藏，然后减少名称冲突的表面积。
some other sort of hiding, then you reduce the surface area for name collisions.
所以第一，我们有名字冲突。
So number one, we have name collisions.
第二，如果你隐藏了什么，这意味着
Number two, if you hide something, it means that
其他人不可能无意中故意滥用那个东西。
somebody else can't accidentally of intentionally misuse that thing.
如果你公开揭露它，每个人都可以使用它。
If you expose it publicly, everybody can use it.
而且他们肯定会使用它，即使你告诉他们不要这样做。
And they definitely will use it, even if you tell them not to.
如果它被暴露了，你可以保证，在某些时候，有人会使用它。
If it's exposed, you can guarantee that, at some point, somebody's gonna use it.
所以如果你隐藏它，那么你就阻止他们访问它。
So if you hide it, then you prevent them from accessing it.
但第三个，也可能是最核心的
But the third one, and probably the most core and
这一原则的重要原因，它经常被忽视。
important reason for this principle, it's often overlooked.
如果你隐藏了一些东西，比如那些实现细节中的一个，或者
If you hide something, like one of those implementation details, or
就像变量名一样，您可以为将来的重构保护自己。
like a variable name, you protect yourself for future refactoring.
如果你揭露了一些东西，这几乎是一种保证，必须有一些CS法律
If you expose something, it's a guarantee almost, there's gotta be some CS law for
这个，它保证有人会使用它。
this, it's a guarantee that somebody's gonna use it.
一旦他们开始使用它，
And as soon as they start using it,
现在，您自由重构它的能力受到限制。
now you are restricted in your ability to freely refactor it.
因为如果你重构，你就破解了他们的代码。
Because if you refactor, you break their code.
如果他们在组织中有足够重要的职位，
And if they have an important enough job title in the organization,
他们会把它压扁的对吧？
they're gonna squash that, right?
&gt；&gt；Kyle Simpson：这种情况我几乎见过几十次
&gt;&gt; Kyle Simpson: It's almost like I've seen that happen a few dozen times
[笑]在我的编程生涯中，好吗？
[LAUGH] in my programming career, okay?
所以隐藏东西最重要的原因之一就是防止
So one of the most important reasons for hiding things is to prevent there being
那种重叠，给你空间说，你知道吗？
that sort of overlap, and give you the space to say, you know what?
我根本不想这么叫它，我也不想让它成为一个数组。
I don't want to call it that at all, and I don't want it to be an array at all.
我想把它改造成一种不同的方式。
I wanna refactor it to be a different way.
这一原则在我们的代码中体现出来。
This principle is playing out in what we're seeing in our code.
在这个特殊的例子中，是名称冲突，但是
In this particular case, it's the name collision, but
这也可能是其他两个原因中的任何一个。
it could have been either of the other two reasons as well.
我们看到它的发展，我们需要解决它，并且
We see it playing out and we need to solve it, and
我们需要用我们对范围的理解来解决它。
the way we need to solve it is it with our understanding of scope.
但是，现在，函数的这种用法并没有真正完成任务，所以
But, right now, this usage of a function is not really accomplishing that task, so
我们需要一种更好的方式来利用我们对范围的知识。
we need a better way of using our knowledge of scope.
我们需要创建一个作用域，就像使用函数一样，但是
We need to create a scope, like with a function, but
我们需要以某种方式不用某些名称污染封闭范围，所以
we need to somehow not pollute the enclosing scope with some name, so
我们没有这个命名冲突的问题。
that we don't have this naming collision issue.
为了弄清楚如何做到这一点，
To figure out how to do that,
我将带你经历一个小小的派生过程。
I'm gonna take you through a small little derivation.
我想让你回到我们之前关于第8行的讨论
I want you to go back to our earlier discussion about how the line 8 would
执行，我希望你在这两个步骤中考虑一下。
execute, and I want you to think about it in those two steps.
记住，第一步是弄清楚大理石里有什么，然后
Remember, the first step was to figure out what's in the marble, and
然后第二步是执行它的括号。
then the second step was the parentheses to execute it.
所以我想让你们把这两个步骤想成两个步骤，我会让它变得非常明显
So I want you to think about those as two steps, and I'm gonna make it super obvious
通过将第一步用圆括号括起来。
by wrapping a parentheses around the first step.
顺便说一下，那个代码仍然有效。
By the way, that code still works.
它看起来很奇怪，但它仍然完全有效。
It looks weird, but it still totally works.
你可以把一个函数放在圆括号里，它仍然可以执行。
You can put parentheses around a function and it's still gonna execute.
它会执行的原因是因为它会做同样的事情
And the reason it's gonna execute is cuz it's gonna do the same thing as in
上一张幻灯片本质上是获取该变量中的值
the previous slide, essentially, which is to go get the value in that variable
首先，然后第二组括号将执行它。
first, and then the second set of parentheses is gonna execute it.